LEWIS CHAPMAN-BARKER

Contact number: 07973 851279 GitHub: https://github.com/lchapmb

Email: lchapmb@googlemail.com
 LinkedIn:

Location: Altrincham, Greater Manchester www.linkedin.com/in/lewischapmanbarker

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Trainee Software Developer with experience as an Account Executive and Administrator, currently studying JavaScript through training provider Northcoders. I am conscientious, creative, and used to working with clients in a professional context.

I want to create technology which is accessible, not just in use but in ease of understanding. This doesn't just increase enjoyment of the technology by allowing a variety of uses, but it allows people to make informed decisions about how they use this technology.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Node
- HTML/CSS
- Express
- Knex

- SQL
- Postgres
- Jest
- Supertest

EXPERIENCE

TRAINEE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER NORTHCODERS, MANCHESTER | 11/2020 - 03/2021

Currently studying software development using JavaScript, with a focus on pair-programming and test-driven development. Projects I have completed include:

Backend Project - a news site which uses Express and Postgres to make requests to a database of news articles, and tested using Jest and Supertest. The project is a work in progress, with more endpoints and functionality planned as it grows alongside the frontend site. Link to repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/be-nc-news Link to hosted site: https://nc-news-today.herokuapp.com/api

Frontend Project - a news site which React to display articles based on topic, as well as associated comments for each article. The site was designed mobile first, responsively, and with accessibility in mind. This will also soon include new CSS for larger view screens, and the ability for users to vote on articles and comments. Link to repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/nc-news

Portfolio - my portfolio site, built with vanilla HTML/CSS. Allows visitors to view contact information, links to social media channels, and the ability to download my CV. Planned development includes more detailed project pages, and some tweaks to the styling. Link to repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/lchapmb.github.io Link to hosted site: https://lchapmb.github.io/

CAREER BREAK | 01/2020 - 10/2020

I decided to take a career break in order to do some travelling, and to find out what I wanted to do next. It soon became clear that I would not be able to travel as extensively as planned due to the Covid-19 pandemic, and I started to explore online courses which may help my career.

This included completing the Responsive Web Design Certification on freeCodeCamp.org, and using Raspberry Pi micro-computers for projects like building a gaming emulator and a music player. I was inspired to spend more time on coding, and so began researching languages to learn. I decided to pursue JavaScript based on how in demand it was among employers, the accessibility of learning resources, and the variety of projects possible using the language. Northcoders in particular stood out as a training provider with an excellent track record in helping Junior Developers launch their career.

ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

PRINT SEARCH LIMITED, TRAFFORD PARK | 07/2018 - 12/2019

- Primarily responsible for administrative and project support services for the Account Directors and Managers
- Prioritised projects, coordinating elements to ensure alignment with client schedules and critical shipment requests
- Assisting incoming call enquiries and customer orders, requiring in-depth knowledge of services and product availabilities
- Controlled stock inventory, arranging materials and supplies replenishments and deliveries
- Responsible for spearheading a new account, project-managed entire process from verifying orders to final production
- Assumed extended hours to honour project deadlines and won Employee of the Month for commitment and service

FUNDING & ONBOARDING EXECUTIVE BPP UNIVERSITY, MANCHESTER | 05/2018 - 07/2018 - Temporary Role

 Managed information database ensuring student documentation content was accurately uploaded and policy compliant

RESOURCE PLANNING COORDINATOR

WELL PHARMACY, MANCHESTER | 02/2018 - 04/2018 - Temporary Role

- Responsible for strategic planning of pharmacists' rota covering a wide region to leverage consistent service in each store
- Proactive and reactive procedures during critical events including coordinating store openings during heavy snowstorms

REGIONAL SERVICE CONTROLLER

GLORY GLOBAL SOLUTIONS, ESSEX | 08/2016 - 12/2017 - Temporary Role

- Promoted to this role from original position of Call Closure & SLA Co-ordinator
- Initial remit focused on streamlining data-entry backlog and co-ordinating parts and materials aligned with project needs
- Managed personnel allocation, co-ordinating field engineers for deployment at planned and reactive maintenance tasks in the banking and retail sectors
- Co-ordinated project to upgrade nationwide estate of machines in advance of launch of new £5 note

REPORTER - INTERNSHIP

THE NUBIAN TIMES, MANCHESTER | 04/2016 - 06/2016

• Developed detailed understanding of fundamentals of editorial process and libel and copyright laws, sourcing content and actively pursuing story leads for publication

CLAIMS PROCESSOR

THE CLAIMS GUYS, ALTRINCHAM | 10/2015 - 04/2016

 Earned early promotion to this role within Financial Ombudsman team from original position of Data Entry Coordinator Managing application eligibility process following customers failed PPI claim referrals to the Ombudsman

RECEPTIONIST

INTERTEK, OLD TRAFFORD | 08/2015 - 10/2015 - Temporary Role

 Managed busy client-facing reception and incoming call enquiries desk within a clinical testing facility

TRAINEE REPORTER

NEWS ASSOCIATES, MANCHESTER | 02/2015 - 07/2015 - Course

• Diploma in Journalism – Level 3

RESEARCH & ADMIN ASSISTANT

CLEAR LAW SOLICITORS, OLD TRAFFORD | 11/2014 - 02/2015 - Temporary Role

 Administered review and restructure of client database to identify potential mis-selling lawsuits, collating client data to initiate redress case proceedings

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX : 2011BA – Philosophy & Human Rights

NEWS ASSOCIATES MANCHESTER: 2015

Diploma in Journalism - Level 3

KNUTSFORD HIGH SCHOOL, ESSEX: 2001 - 2008

A / AS LEVELS

Philosophy and Ethics – B General

Studies – D

English Language – A

English Literature – A

History A*

English Language & Literature – C Biology Chemistry - A
– D Physics - B
Chemistry (AS) - C French - B

GCSEs Biology - B Art & Design - C

Maths - A

OTHER EXPERIENCE

My previous experience includes interning as a Reporter, and I graduated with a degree in Philosophy and Human Rights. My hobbies include playing guitar and singing, as well as drawing, writing, and I was the President of the Judo club at university. What this boils down to is that I am someone who is conscientious, creative, and who is used to working with clients in a professional context.

Growing up, my use of computers earned me a reputation within my family, and I naturally became the resident tech support. I remember my first time learning about how websites were put together; it was thanks to MySpace's use of HTML in profile design. My friends and I would find little bits to add to our profiles, changing the layout or colours manually, or with snippets we had found online. More recently, I have spent some time playing the Raspberry Pi computers, creating a Spotify player and a retro gaming emulator.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.